三辆车依次为
1979 AC 3000ME，1972 Hillman Avenger Tiger，1961 Hillman Super Minx
欢迎来到
尼斯湖
大峡谷
翻译
Monica-卡 老虎
InX 17 cc
时间轴
Monica-卡 RN
校对
Monica-卡  InX  cc 17 RN
大家好
Hello, everybody.
你好
Hello. Hello.
大家好
Greetings!
这儿还是这样
That doesn't get any worse.
你好
Hello.
欢迎大家
Hello, and welcome!
欢迎来到Grand Tour
Welcome to The Grand Tour,
这次 我们还是在
which, once again, comes to you
苏格兰的尼斯湖畔
from the shores of Loch Ness in Scotland.
好的
Now...
我们之所以还在这儿
The reason why we're still here is,
是因为上次节目后
after last week's show,
他俩和一个当地人交流了一下
these two got talking to a man in the local town,
他和他们说
who has convinced them that,
这湖里有个怪兽
in that lake, there is a monster.
这里的确有个怪兽
Well, there is a monster.
你见过吗
Have you seen it?
没 但那人很有说服力
No, but the man was very convincing.
他是不是卖给你一块
Did he sell you a tea towel
印着怪兽的抹布
with a drawing of the monster on it?
是的 现在我们知道怪兽长啥样了
He did, and now we know what the monster looks like.
正是 我们还有怪兽的照片
Exactly. We've also got photographs of the monster.
-看这张照片 -这是块木头
- Look, we've got this one. - That's a log.
还有这张 看哪
And we've got this one. Look at that!
-怪兽 -还是木头
- Monster. - Another log.
你们来看看这张照片吧 就是它
Can I just draw your attention to a picture I've got? Here it is.
这不是怪兽吧
Well, that's not a monster, is it?
不 那是个象鼩 好眼力
No, that is an elephant shrew. Well spotted.
这可是动物中的GT-R
Now, this is the Nissan GT-R among animals.
你见过它跑起来吗 非常惊人
Have you ever seen it on the move? It's phenomenal!
它留下一条尾流 过弯时就像有下压力
It leaves a rooster tail and it corners like it's got downforce.
我的意思是 这是种非常珍稀的动物
But my point is, this is a very rare animal,
而且它的照片是高清全彩的
and yet the photograph of it is in sharp focus and colour.
你们那些怪兽照片都是黑白的
Now, all the pictures of your monster are in black and white.
-可能怪兽就是黑白的 -而且模糊
- Well, maybe it is black and white. - And blurry.
可能就是模糊的
Maybe it's blurry.
这让我纠结了一星期 所以我决定
This has been driving me mad all week, so I decided
去苏格兰兜兜风 说实话
to go for a drive on some of Scotland's, let's be honest,
公路超棒
brilliant driving roads.
它们太美妙了
They are...They are fantastic.
说到这个 事实上
And actually, speaking of which,
有叫北部高地倡议的东西
something called the North Highland Initiative,
是查尔斯王子发起的
set up by Prince Charles,
由此几年前诞生了北海岸500号公路
a few years ago it came up with the North Coast 500.
现在 它是苏格兰版的美国66号公路
Now, this was going to be Scotland's answer to Route 66 in America.
数百公里的绝世风景 令人惊叹
Miles of amazing scenery. Incredible road.
这里有张局部照片
Got a picture of a bit of it here.
看哪
Look at that.
大获成功
Huge success.
土豪们慕名而来
Loads of big spenders came
开着他们的兰博基尼 法拉利和保时捷
with their Lamborghinis, and their Ferraris and their Porsches.
旅馆住满 饭店爆棚
Hotels were full, restaurants were packed.
当地经济腾飞
Local economy booming.
所以你觉得要过多久
So how long do you think it was
当地的报纸的头条
before the local newspaper
会包含以下两个词
carried a headline containing the following words:
"警方"和"镇压"
"police" and "crackdown"?
十天
Ten days.
-两天吧 -两天
- Two days. - Two days.
"噢 我们不能让人在上面开车
"Oh, we can't have people driving along that!
你很可能会撞到路人"
You might run into a pedestrian!"
这是条路
It's a road!
我就知道 然后就有了A9公路
I know it is. And then you've got the A9.
160公里布满测速相机
Ninety-nine miles of continuous average speed camera.
-160吗？-160公里
- Ninety-nine? - Ninety-nine miles.
不好意思各位 我猜你们都是车迷吧
Now, I'm sorry, you lot, I presume you're all petrolheads, yes?
是的
Yes!
那我来问你们一个问题
So let me ask you a question.
在很多年后
Dying in your beds,
电影《勇敢的心》经典台词 讲述苏格兰起义领袖与英格兰抗争的故事
你临终之际
many years from now...
你愿意用这所有
...would you be willing to trade all the days,
剩下的日子
from this day to that,
来换取一个机会
for one chance,
只有一次机会
just one chance,
回到这里 告诉苏格兰安全摄像头企业
to come back and say to the Scottish Safety Camera Partnership,
"你们可以拿走我们的驾照
"You can take our licences,
但你们夺不走我们的自由"
but you can't take our freedom"?
自由 自由
AUDIENCE: Freedom! Freedom!
自由 自由 自由
Freedom! Freedom! Freedom! Freedom! Freedom!
看看你干了些什么
Now look what you've done!
谢谢大家
Thank you.
看看你的所作所为
Look what you've done!
-我知道 -这很危险
- I know. - That's dangerous!
-我知道 -让我们继续节目
- I know. - Let's get on with the show.
好的 在今晚的汽车节目中
Yes. In tonight's car programme...
罐子里有只蚂蚁
An ant in a jar.
一只狗在引路
A dog on a lead.
桌子上有些豆
And some beans on a table.
但是首先
But first,
当有人想买一辆
when someone wants to buy
又大又快的轿车
a large and very fast saloon car,
他们喜欢买德国车
they tend to buy German.
他们觉得没其他选择
They think there is no alternative.
但真的没有吗
But is there?
这是一辆雷克萨斯GS F
This is the Lexus GS F.
一眼就知道 这不是辆很好看的车
And straight away, we can see that it isn't an especially handsome car.
而且这是辆雷克萨斯
And it's a Lexus,
表明车主是个高尔夫发烧友
which marks its owner out as a golf enthusiast
或者是个呆子
and possibly... a bore.
更糟的是
And things are worse
当你试图和它共处的时候
when you try to live with it for a while.
烦人的是 除了方向盘上的那些按钮
The most annoying thing, apart from the buttons on the steering wheel,
似乎所有按钮都会把收音机调到你不喜欢的电台
all of which seem to retune the radio to a station you don't like very much,
不光这个 每当你想伸手
apart from that, every time you reach for
拿杯架上的提神饮料时
a can of zesty drink in the cup holder...
我又手贱了
I've done it again!
你总会不小心碰到鼠标
You can't help but nudge the mouse
它会把导航的目的地设置到
which sets the destination on the satnav
你现在的位置
to where you are.
在300米后 右转
SATNAV: In 300 yards, right turn.
我不用你告诉我怎么走
I don't need to be told how to get here.
我已经在这儿了
I'm already here.
右转 然后右转
Next right, then right turn.
噢天哪 现在它想让我退回去
Oh, God. Now it's trying to make me go back there a few yards.
我开过了啊
I was there!
所以 除了这个费事又讨厌的导航
So, apart from a fiddly and annoying satnav...
前方右转 然后右转
SATNAV: Next right, then right turn.
这7万英镑还能买到什么
...what else do you get for your ￡70,000?
额 讲真没什么了
Er... Not much, really.
车里没有Wi-Fi
Er... You don't get Wi-Fi
没有苹果Carplay 或者手势控制
or Apple CarPlay, or gesture control.
连双离合变速箱都没有
You don't even get a DSG gearbox.
行驶时座椅不能按摩
Seats don't massage you as you drive along,
也不会自动泊车
it can't park itself.
但有一个DVD播放器
But you do get a DVD player.
这多怀旧啊
And how 1996 is that?
这辆车配置匮乏 还烦人
This car, then, is sparsely equipped and annoying.
然而 同时它也相当棒
However, it's also rather good.
首先 是它的引擎
First of all, there's the engine.
宝马和奔驰都使用涡轮增压
BMW and Mercedes both use turbocharging
来达到动力需求
to balance the need for power
和排放要求的平衡
with the need for good emissions...
但这辆车不是
but this doesn't.
它把燃料和空气混合
This mixes the fuel with the air,
然后 没耍什么花招
and then, with no trickery at all,
就这么点燃了
blows it up!
当然 这意味着
Of course, that does mean
GS F对动物们不太友好
the GS F isn't very kind to animals.
但毫无疑问 这是件坏事
And that's a bad thing, make no mistake.
但从好的方面看
But on the upside,
听听它发出的噪音
listen to the noise it makes!
中转速时 它听起来很凶恶
At medium revs, it sounds baleful,
就像一条孤单的狗
like a... lonely dog.
但当你拉高转速时 它就像它自己
But when you build the revs up, it sounds like what it is:
一台5升的自然吸气V8
a normally aspirated five-litre V8.
它发出的功率和扭矩
It doesn't produce anything like the power or the torque
比不上德国的竞争对手
you get from its turbocharged German rivals,
但就纯粹的激情而言
but for sheer excitement...
就像被女神挠痒了一样
It's like being tickled by a goddess.
而且它也不是很慢
And it's not exactly slow.
它百公里加速4.5秒
It does 0-60 in four-and-a-half seconds.
最高时速能达到272公里
And flat out, it'll do nearly 170 miles an hour.
然后是操控性
And then there's the handling.
很难相信这是一辆
It's hard to believe that this is a large
大型五座豪华轿车
and extremely comfortable five-seater
后备箱大到能放下高尔夫球杆
with a boot that's big enough for your golf bats
和所有的共济会用品
and all your Freemasonry paraphernalia,
因为 它感觉像一辆跑车
because... it feels like a sports car.
你可以用各种开关和按钮
You can change the way the car behaves
来调整车辆的表现
with various knobs here and buttons here,
但我把所有东西都关了
but I've got everything turned off
所以我能体验一下没有电子辅助
so I can get a feel for how the car behaves
这辆车会如何表现
without an electronic safety blanket.
而且我很喜欢
And I like it!
看看这个
Look at that.
不仅低速时转向优秀
The steering's not brilliant at low speeds,
当你把车尾甩起来的时候
but when you've got the arse hanging out like that...
这太棒了
it's fantastic!
是的
Yes!
是时候再来杯提神饮料了
Time for another zesty drink.
噢 我去
Oh, damn it!
-三百米后...  -我知道我在哪儿
- SATNAV: In 300 yards... - I know where I am!
前方右转 然后右转
Next right. Then right turn.
噢 饶了我吧
Oh, for God's sake!
如果是日常生活用车
For living with on a day-to-day basis,
德国车要好得多
German cars are far better.
但作为一台驾驶机器 你会对这结论感到惊讶
But as a driving machine, and you may find this conclusion surprising...
我认为GS F吊打它们
I think the GS F has them licked.
在路测过程中
有一些动物受到了伤害
好吧
Well, well.
现在
Now...
我要说 今年晚些时候新的宝马M5要发布了
Now, I should point out, there is a new BMW M5 coming later this year,
但它要超过GS F可不容易
but it'll have to go some to be better than that GS F.
-的确 -是的
- It really will. - Yeah, yeah, yeah.
但在制作的时候有多少动物受到了伤害
But exactly how many animals were harmed in the making of it?
-很多动物 -还有一只是乌龟
- A lot! - One of them was a tortoise!
我知道 我们先无视吧
I know. Let's gloss over that, OK?
我们来看看它在埃博拉症赛道上能跑多快
And let's find out now how fast the Lexus goes round the Eboladrome.
当然 这就要把它交给那个人
And that, of course, means handing it over to a man
他认为水果是来自苏联的
who thinks that fruit is from the Soviet Union.
是的 有请老美
Yeah, it's the American.
他蓄势待发
He's coiled and ready.
他出发了
And he's off!
释放出所有471匹马力
Unleashing all the 471 wailing horsepower
开始不直道上的第一次冲刺
for the first sprint of the Isn't Straight.
这里面都是什么破烂玩意儿
What the hell does all this shit do in here?
他需要的只是两个踏板和一个方向盘
All he needs is two pedals and a wheel
就能霸气外露
to unleash the full shock and awe.
牵引力控制系统
Traction control?
如果你想要有自己思想的东西
If you want something with a mind of its own...
买匹马 找个老婆
get a horse, get married.
幸运的是 他不需要电子辅助
Fortunately, he doesn't need the electronic nannies.
全力进入留你名弯
Pushing it hard up to Your Name Here,
现在全靠这强大的布伦博卡钳
and now leaning on the mighty Brembo brakes.
这里轻一点 让扭矩矢量差速器发挥作用
Gentle now, letting the torque-vectoring diff do its thing.
再次踩下油门
And then back on the throttle
强大的V8得以再次一展歌喉
so that mighty V8 can sing its song once more.
如果他们让我带枪的话
If they would have let me bring my gun,
我现在可能已经自杀了
I'd have probably shot myself by now.
那实在是浪费人才
And that would be a waste of great talent.
好的 再次快速通过不直道
Right, another fast dash up the Isn't,
八速自动变速箱快速降档
and now shifting rapidly down the eight-speed automatic
到达老奶房弯
as he arrives at Old Lady's House.
精准给油通过颠簸的赛道
Feeding it precisely through there on this damp track,
在掀起破损路面前到达了变电箱弯
before opening it up for the broken surface down to Substation.
固定阻尼器表现很出色
Giving the fixed-rate dampers a good workout here.
还剩两个弯
Two corners left.
这里走线很紧
Tidy through there.
只剩绵羊坡弯了
Just Field of Sheep to go.
抓地力到极限了 冲过终点
And he's right on the edge of the grip and across the line!
看起来的确不错
It did look good. It did look good.
-的确不错 -成绩怎么样
- It did look good. - How did it do?
啊哈
A-ha!
好的 来看看在圈速榜上表现如何
Well, now let's find out where it goes on the Lap Board.
别忘了 这是湿地圈
Remember, it was damp.
噢 哇哦
Oh, wow! Wow!
这比旧款的宝马还要慢
So it's slower than an already-out-of-date BMW,
它让你像个共济会员
it makes you look like a Freemason,
它还会让动物爆炸
and it causes animals to explode.
是的 但是
Yes. Yes, but--
是的 但你又给了一个优秀的推荐 杰里米
Yes, but it's just another of your excellent recommendations, Jeremy.
非常感谢 没有关系
Thank you very much. Never mind.
是的 真是谢谢你了
Yes, thank you very much, indeed.
现在我们得继续了
And now we must move on,
因为是时候把导航终点设置为唠嗑了
because it is time to set the satnav for destination chat,
我们也驶向唠嗑街
as we head down Conversation Street.
-那很疼 -很疼吗
- It hurt. - That hurt?
-很疼啊 -是吗 没上星期我挨酒瓶那下疼
- It hurt. - It did? But not as much as the wine bottle last week.
现在奔驰想出了一个方案
Now, Mercedes, they've come up with this plan, or this idea,
当你不用车的时候 可以把车租出去
where you can rent your car out when you're not using it.
这是不是有点像Airbnb
Is that a bit like erm... Airbnb?
一模一样
Exactly like Airbnb.
奔驰没有意识到
The thing Mercedes haven't realised is that we,
我相信你肯定同意
and I'm sure you all agree with me,
我们和车之间形成了感情纽带
we form an emotional bond with our car.
-我们心系爱车 -正是
- We're attached to them. - Exactly.
所以把车租给别人
So renting it to someone else
就像把你的宠物租给别人
would be like renting out your pet.
是的 或者你的丁丁
Yeah, or your penis.
-是的 -我心系着它 就是这个意思
- Yes. - I'm attached to it, I mean. That's what I mean.
是个人都这样想
One would hope so, yeah.
你肯定不想看到它和别人欢度时光
You wouldn't want to see somebody else having fun with it.
-是啊 它是我的 -说得好
- No, it's mine! - Exactly. Exactly.
这就是我想说的 奔驰显然没好好动脑子
And that's what I'm on about. Mercedes has obviously got it into its head,
这实在让我担忧 因为奔驰是大企业
and this really worries me, because it's a large car company,
如果车只是工具 就像微波炉 或者冰箱一样
that cars are just tools, like microwave ovens or fridge freezers,
那我们就很乐意 "借呗 反正我不在乎"
that we'll just sort of gladly, "Borrow it. I don't really care."
你太对了 它们都有感情的
You're absolutely right. They are very emotional.
因为如果你有辆车 最后卖掉了
Because you know if you have a car, eventually you sell it,
但当你看见别人开它的时候 总会难过
but then you see somebody else driving around in it, that always feels bad.
就像你看见前女友和别人嘿嘿嘿一样
It's a bit like watching your ex-girlfriend do sex with someone else.
对的 在衣柜里熬了一晚上以后 深有体会
No. And after a terrible evening in a wardrobe, I know.
奇怪地深蚀人心
It's strangely undermining.
不好意思打断一下 看到湖里的圆圈了吗
I'm sorry to interrupt. See those circles in the lake just there?
-水怪 水怪啊
- Monster! Monster! It's a monster!
-我刚刚看见... 有人看见了吗 -是水怪 水怪
- I just saw... Did anyone else see that? - Monster! Monster!
早说了 是真的
It's real. I told you.
我们没法统一意见 湖里有水怪吗
Since we can't agree on this, is there a monster in the loch?
有
AUDIENCE: Yes!
好的 他们住这儿 肯定知道
Right, there you go. They live here, they would know.
如果没水怪 那这里的旅游业怎么搞
And if there were no monster, what would you do for a tourist industry up here?
卖没有水怪图案的抹布
Sell tea towels without monsters on them.
不 我不买账 因为你说的是
No, I'm not having that, because what you're saying is,
"来美丽的苏格兰吧" 就像你说的 路美风景美
"Come to beautiful Scotland." As you've said, lovely roads, lovely scenery.
这儿有个酒店 有个美丽的湖
There's a hotel, a beautiful lake.
他们为什么要说 "是啊 但这有个水怪"
Why would they say, "Yeah, but there's a monster"?
就好像在说 "来约克郡吧
That would be like saying, "Come to Yorkshire.
它很美丽 你知道我们这儿有瘟疫吗"
It's beautiful. We've got the plague, you know?"
-肯定不会这么说 -我们有点分心了
- They they wouldn't do that. - We've got distracted a little bit.
-有点跑题 -我们在说什么来着
- We have got a bit off-topic. - What were we talking about?
我们在说他躲在衣柜里
We were talking about him hiding in a wardrobe,
看他的前女友嘿嘿嘿
watching an ex-girlfriend have sex.
-是的 说漏了 -是有点说漏了
- Yeah, that was an over-share. - It was a bit of an over-share.
要不就是他把丁丁租出去的事 我忘了
It was either that or he'd rented his penis out. I can't remember.
类似这些事
Something along those lines.
但实际上 我们想和车建立情感纽带
But actually, there's a point I just want to make on this
是有原因的
about this emotional connection we have with our cars.
你知道报废一辆车是什么感觉吗 非常悲惨
Cos you know when you scrap a car? It really is very tragic.
你目送着与你经历风雨的车进入粉碎机
When you watch a car that's got all those shared memories going into the crusher.
-穷途末路了 -是的
- It's the end of the road. - It is.
有个新的组织
There's this... a new organisation.
叫做慈善汽车 你可以把车给他们
It's called Charity Car, where you can give your car to them,
他们搞定所有的手续 然后拿走你的车
they deal with all the paperwork and what have you and take your car away.
然后他们把募集的钱捐给你指定的慈善组织
Yeah? And then they give the money that they raised to a charity of your choice.
-好主意 我喜欢 -好点子
- That's a nice idea. I like that. - It is a nice idea.
这样一来 虽然车没了很难过
So that, you know, it's sad your old car's gone,
但是有一头驴子能被拯救
but now... you know, a donkey can be rescued.
你的车就能在野驴的微笑中永远活着
And your car lives on in the smile of an abandoned donkey.
太感人了 这就是我们要做的
That's a beautiful thing. That's what we're about.
这就是节目的精髓 走心
That's what this show is, it's all heart.
-就是我们 -爱心和道路安全:
- It's what we are. - Heart and road safety: those are the two pillars
支撑我们节目的两大支柱
that underpin everything, really, on this show.
-我要跟你唠嗑一下 -是吗
- I've got some conversation for you. - Have you?
是的 有这么一个网站
Yes, which is that there's a website that tells you
它会告诉你在英国的公路上
how many of any given type of car
还剩下多少种型号的汽车
are still left on the roads of Britain today, yes?
恐怕有一些坏消息
And I'm afraid we have some sad news.
是的 实在是忧心
Yeah, we do. This is a big worry.
你还记得雪铁龙Saxo VTS吗 就是它
You remember the Citroën Saxo VTS, yeah? There it is.
愤怒小混混之车
The car of the angry yob.
很适合飞身下车再偷把电锯进去
It is the ideal car to nip out and steal a chainsaw in.
一辆绝妙的 像样的 刺激的小掀背 我很喜欢
A fabulous, proper, fizzy little hatchback. Loved it.
在2008年 还有5000辆这车
Well, in 2008, there were 5,000 of them on the road.
-今年 只剩491辆了 -看到没
- This year, 491 left on the road. - See?
而且事实上 这令人担忧
And, in fact... I know, this is a worry.
看 这有个图表 我们画的
Look, we've got a little chart. We've drawn this up.
按这个速度 到2019年 它就灭绝了
At that rate, by 2019, they'll all have gone.
还有沃克斯豪尔Calibra 16V
There's also the Vauxhall Calibra 16V.
这里有张照片 我们过去很爱它
There's a picture. We used to love that.
你知道吗 这款车只剩323辆了
Do you know, there are only 323 of those left,
一年之内就会灭绝
and they could be extinct within a year.
有趣的是 全世界的人都在努力
And what's interesting is there are people all over the world
保护老虎不至灭绝
working hard to save the tiger from extinction,
然而却没有人
but nobody is doing anything
保护Calibra 16V
to save the Vauxhall Calibra 16V.
-我们似乎发现了些什么 -不并没有
- We've identified something here. - No, there isn't.
然而 还是有好消息的 莫瑞斯Ital
However, there is some good news in all of this. The Morris Ital.
一共有175000...
175,000 of these...
...坨这样的屎
turds were made,
被奥斯汀汽车拉出来
were squeezed out by the Austin.
在2015年 它只剩35辆了
And in 2015, there were only 35 left.
是的 现在欢呼吧
Yes! Now you can cheer!
-这是好消息 -的确
- That is good news. - It's good news.
路上只有35辆
Only 35 on the road.
不 等等等等 你说得很对
No. Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait. You're absolutely right.
别急着庆祝 是的 2015年只剩35辆
But before you celebrate, yes, 35 left on the road in 2015.
-嗯哼 -在2016年 有47辆
- Mm-hm. - In 2016... there were 47.
什么 居然还能增长
What, so they're going up?
-它们在繁衍吗 -不
- Are they mating? - No. No.
我认为是有人在复原它
I think people are restoring them.
-什么人 -疯子
- What people? - Mad people.
-无论如何 有可能你是对的 但我做了一个计算
Anyway, look... No, you're possibly right, but I've done a calculation.
这速率是 一年内增长了34%
And at that rate... That's a 34% increase in just one year.
按这个速度 到2044年
And at that rate, by the year 2044,
所有175000辆Ital都会回到路上
all 175,000 Morris Itals will be back on the road.
-噢我的天 -简直是灾难
- Oh, my God! - This is a disaster.
是的 女士们先生们 这就是英国脱欧
It is. That, ladies and gentlemen, is Brexit.
这就是他们想要的: 英国倒退
That's what they want: backwards with Britain.
是时候了 因为唠嗑街已经走到底
It is time now, since we've reached the end of Conversation Street,
我们挂入倒挡 来看看这个
to select reverse and have a look at this.
这是宾利Bentayga
This is the Bentley Bentayga.
巨型奢华四驱的
A massive, luxurious, four-wheel-drive
SUV猎装车
SUV shooting brake.
问题是
The question is,
这是辆好车 还是只是一坨...
is it any good, or is it a load of...
一坨啥呢
What's the word?
紫薇
为了找到答案 詹姆斯把它带到了
Well, to find out, James brought it here...
德国的阿尔卑斯山
to the German Alps.
好的 我直接说明白
Right, I'll get straight to the point.
它太棒了
It is tremendous.
对于这车有件重要的事要记住
The important thing to remember about this car is this.
它不是辆越野车 也不是SUV
It's not an off-roader, it's not an SUV.
最重要的是 它是辆宾利
First and foremost, it's a Bentley.
这就是这辆车的灵魂
That's what this car is about.
我已经爱上它了
I'm already loving it.
然而 你猜怎么着
But then... guess what?
问题在于 这辆宾利裸车
The problem is that a barebones Bentley
价格为16万英镑
costs ￡160,000,
而少花12000英镑
and for ￡12,000 less than that,
你却可以得到这个
you can have this.
一辆能唱能跳 配置齐全
An all-singing, all-dancing, everything-fitted-as-standard
5升机械增压的路虎揽胜
5L supercharged Range Rover.
或者再少花12万英镑 你可以得到这个
Or, for ￡120,000 less than that, you can have this,
新款捷豹F-PACE
the new Jaguar F-PACE.
这可不是花园棚屋
And it's not like this thing is a garden shed.
它配备了各种智能部件
It's got loads of clever stuff on it.
如果你从超市回来
So if you're coming back from the shops
手里抱着沉重的袋子
with your arms full of heavy bags,
你可以用脚打开后备箱
you can open the boot with your foot.
-揽胜也有这功能 -是 但它贵了12万英镑
- Yeah, but I can do that with a Range Rover. - Yes, but it's ￡120,000 more!
-而且你还没有这个 看 -那是啥
- And you don't get one of these. Look. - What is it?
这是个防水的便携手环
It's a waterproof, go-anywhere bracelet
你可以用它锁车
that you use to lock...
解锁车 还能发动引擎
and unlock it, and start the engine,
所以你不用随身带钥匙了
so you don't need to carry keys in your pocket.
这...
That...
-这还真是个好点子 -是啊 很机智
- That's actually quite a good idea. - I know, it's brilliant.
-你怎么给它充电 -不知道 可能就像手表一样
- How do you charge it up? - I don't know. Maybe it's like one of those watches.
-噢 看哪 -噢
-Oh, hello. - Oh.
吹牛老爹来了
Puff Daddy is arriving.
吹牛老爹 原名肖恩·科姆斯 美国说唱歌手
你觉得他戴大金链子了吗
Do you think he's wearing a chain?
那玩意儿是捷豹的四倍价钱
You know, that thing costs four times more than the Jag.
而且不像徽章那样差异明显
And it's not like the badges are that different.
捷豹是一辆车
That Jag is... a car.
这更像是一种声明
This is more of a statement.
这是对生而为人的
This is a new way of understanding
新式诠释
the condition of being human.
奢华的最终证明
It is the last word in luxury.
这个证明还真是贵
It's a very expensive statement, though.
买这玩意的钱 能买那台捷豹
I mean, if you've got the money to buy that, you could buy the Jag
还剩130,000磅 能雇个公关经理
and still have ￡130,000 to spend on a PR agent
上晨间访谈节目吹嘘自己了
to put you on breakfast TV talking about how great you are.
它贵130,000磅是有原因的
It costs ￡130,000 more for a reason.
捷豹车主都是爱幻想的中年男人
Jags are for deluded middle-aged men
整天沉浸在种马的幻想中
who entertain tragic fantasies about being Lotharios.
我懂 我有四辆
I know, I've had four of them!
-要说喜欢幻想的品牌 -嘿
-If you're talking about brands with delusion - hello!
-首选的就是宾利  -两位
-Bentley, that's what it is. -Guys.
-怎么  -在停车场可不能分辨高下
-What? -We are not gonna sort this out in a car park.
我们得去试驾
We need to go for a drive,
我在地图上已经确定好路线了
and I have worked out a route on this map here, OK?
我们在紫薇村
We are in the village of... Wank,
从紫薇村出发 到亲亲乡
and we'll go from... Wank to Kissing,
再到摸摸寨
then on to Petting.
然后... 到这
Then... this place.
最后到领证村
And then... Wedding.
所以是紫薇 亲亲 摸摸 (哔~) 领证
So, Wank, Kissing, Petting, (BLEEP), Wedding.
没错 在中欧可以走遍人生旅途
Yes. It'll be a journey through life without leaving Central Europe.
是的 出发吧
Yeah, it will. Let's do it.
我们十分性奋
Very excited,
踏上了德国人所谓的浪漫之旅
we set off on what the Germans call the Romantic Road.
北                浪漫公路                南
我们离开了紫薇村
So, we are leaving the town of Wank.
那是什么 "谢谢..."
What's that? "Thank you for..."
什么 哦好的
What? Oh, yeah.
欢迎来访
只过了几分钟
And after just a few minutes,
就发生了很不寻常的事情
something very unusual happened.
伙计们
Guys...
我想不出话说
I can't think of anything to say.
松了一口气
What a relief.
不 我是真的想不出
No, but I really can't,
因为如果你想要一辆大型豪华越野车
because if you want a large, luxury off-roader,
你就买揽胜
you buy a Range Rover.
结束
The end.
结案 继续
The end, move on.
然而詹姆斯
James, however,
对他的Bentayga有很多话要说
had lots to say about his Bentayga.
嘿老兄 你知道吗
Hey, chaps, did you know
我车上有18个扬声器
the stereo in my car has got 18 speakers?
才这么点 我有27个
Is that all? Mine's got 27.
嗯 都在放垃圾歌
Yeah, all playing rubbish.
谢谢 哈蒙德
Thanks, Hammond.
其实27个扬声器不是重点
Actually, 27 speakers is not the point.
它的音响有1950瓦功率
My car stereo produces 1,950W,
它是车载音响功率最大的车
making it the most powerful stereo ever put in a car.
实际上 音响是车内唯一能响的东西了
In fact, it's about the only thing in here that does make a noise.
这有点像在大英图书馆里开车
This is a little bit like driving along in the British Library.
非常安静 非常优雅
It's very quiet, it's very refined.
地毯非常厚
The carpets are very thick.
这意味着 当你踩下踏板的时候
Which means you simply aren't ready for what happens
你不知道会发生什么
when you put your foot down.
它配备了全新的600马力W12引擎
So this has an all-new W12 600-horsepower engine,
就像身处于皮革包裹的火山爆发中
and it's like being in a leather-trimmed volcanic eruption.
它不加速 而是直接爆炸
It doesn't accelerate, it goes off.
我的姑奶奶
Bloody Nora!
可惜的是 杰里米想出要说的了
Sadly, at this point, Jeremy thought of something to say.
看到了吗 那是希特勒
See that? That's the prison
写下《我的奋斗》的监狱
where Hitler wrote Mein Kampf.
嗯 你想说什么呢
Yeah. Where are you going with that?
没什么
Nowhere, really.
只是觉得你们会想知道
Just thought you might like to know.
好的 我们回到车上
Good. Let's get back to the cars.
因为现在捷豹和路虎是一家公司的
Now, you might be thinking that because Jaguar is owned by the same company
所以你会觉得这是辆贴捷豹牌的神行者
that own Land Rover, this is just a Freelander with a Jaguar badge on it,
但并不是
but it's not.
车身下是和捷豹XE相同的
Underneath is the same basic aluminium structure
全铝车架
you find under a Jaguar XE,
XE是好车 所以这很好
which is a fantastic car, so that's good.
我的确只有3升的机械增压V6
I do only get a 3L supercharged V6,
也就是375马力
which means 375 brake horsepower.
比船长那辆少了225马力 讲真
That's 225 less than James's, let's be honest,
那就是辆真皮的Q7
leather-lined Audi Q7.
但是这辆车很轻
But this is light,
所以没那么笨拙
so it ain't no slouch.
我喜欢它的操控
I like the way this thing handles itself.
我喜欢它转向的方式
I like the way, when you change direction,
它控制了车重
when you turn, it controls its weight,
过弯时重心转移
what there is of it, across the axles.
让人觉得敏捷又有活力
That makes it feel nimble, eager.
不会有坐在豪宅里掉下悬崖的感觉
It doesn't feel like I'm sitting in a stately home falling off a cliff.
不久 我追上了船长
Soon, James was in my way.
噢看呐
Oh, look.
你应该来我这儿 这儿能看见白金汉宫
James, you should be where I am. You can see Buckingham Palace and...
哦不 是你的车屁股
Oh, no, it's the back of your car.
我喜欢有人跟在后面 你是要去度假吗
I like it when my man is following me. Do you have the luggage for the weekend?
得了吧 詹姆斯
Come on, James.
可能你的马力用不完 但你挡路了
You might have all the horsepower in the world, but you are in the way.
省省吧 伯明翰小子
Stay with that, Birmingham boy.
詹姆斯 你是怕开太快了家具会晃吗
James, are you worried all your furniture will slide about if you go any faster?
噢隧道
Oh, tunnel.
很好 我有正事要做
Excellent. I have important work to do.
贱民们真是干什么都要发出点声音
Honestly, the plebs make such a noise about everything.
这就是"运动多功能车"里的"运动"
That is putting the S back in SUV.
这是辆很运动的SUV
This is a sporty sports-utility vehicle.
这项运动还不是钓鱼
And the sport is not fishing.
可惜 娱乐时间被大猩猩
Sadly, our playtime was then interrupted
恼人的电话打断了
by a worrying call from Clarkson.
伙计们 我收到制片人的短信
Erm... guys, we've had a text from Mr Wilman.
噢天呐 他说什么
Oh, God. What does it say?
他说为了区分性能的差异
It said that to sort out the performance differences,
我们要去附近的一个机场
we should go to a nearby airstrip,
他准备了一场竞速
where he'd laid on some competition.
我们去了
So we did.
伙计们 这是我们的竞争对手
Chaps, this is what we're up against.
宝马X5 M
BMW X5 M.
4.4升双涡轮增压 567马力
4.4L, twin-turbocharged, 567 horsepower.
真是严峻的考验
That is fairly serious competition.
好好想想 这是英国对阵德国
If you think about it, it's gonna be Britain versus Germany.
其实不对 你们的是印度车 我的也是德国车
Well, not really. Your two cars are Indian and mine's German as well.
行吧 那就是印度对阵德国
All right, it's gonna be India versus Germany,
我会用强大又轻盈的捷豹取得胜利
and I shall be victorious in my mighty lighty Jaguar.
-好吧 -行 但是你赢不了
- Right. - Well, you see, you won't be.
这辈子都赢不了
Not in a million years.
抱歉浪费你们的时间来比赛了
Sorry about wasting your time with this race.
你可以发布一辆车 时速一百万英里
You could launch a car that does a million miles an hour
只卖8毛钱 还能在水上开
and costs 8 pence and runs on water,
但人们还是会买揽胜
and people would still buy Range Rovers,
因为不然买啥呢
because why would you not?
好的 空调关闭
OK, air-conditioning is off.
现在是动态模式 变速箱在运动模式
It's in dynamic mode, gearbox is in sport.
给力啊 小捷豹
Come on, little Jag.
我并不担心粉红小猪的威胁
So I'm not really worried about Pinky and Perky's challenge,
Pinky and Perky BBC动画 神气粉小猪
但BMW让我很紧张
but the BMW does worry me.
差不多的功率 还比我轻得多
Almost as much power, very obviously lighter.
英国的很多有钱人
A lot of well-to-do people in Britain
都想知道这场比赛的结果
will want to know the result of this race
就在他们决定明年的狩猎季
before they choose what colour Range Rover they'd like
要买什么颜色的揽胜之前
for next year's shooting season.
宾利去哪儿了
Where's the Bentley gone?
我要输了 同志们
I'm losing, everybody.
加油啊
Come on!
150码... 哦不
150... Oh, no!
哦不 他怎么开这么快的
Oh, no! Where is he getting that from?
小菜一碟
Easy.
垫底了 铁定垫底了
Last. Stone-dead last.
妈蛋
Bugger it.
好的 做得好 詹姆斯
Yes, yes. Well done, James.
谁会想到 如果花四倍的钱买车
Oh, who knew, if you spend four times as much on a car,
就会比另一辆车稍微快一点点呢
you get one that's a tiny bit faster than another?
嘘 你们还没明白吗
Ssh! You two just haven't got the message, have you?
-明白什么 你输了吗 -好吧...
- What, that you lost? - Yeah. Well...
不 这很明白了 就像内裤
No, the message is very clear. Underpants, OK?
你可以在商场货架上买条便宜的
You can buy a cheap pair from a market stall,
或者可以买一条含有金丝的昂贵内裤
or you can buy an expensive pair with gold thread in them,
或者像其他人一样 去玛莎百货买
or you can do what everyone does, you go to Marks & Spencer's.
玛莎百货 如果你不是英国人
Marks & Spencer's, if you're watching this not in the UK,
那就是所有人买内裤的地方
is where we all buy our pants from.
但我不去那儿买
Well, I don't.
比赛过后 我们继续旅途
After the race, we resumed our journey,
而理查德和詹姆斯则继续斗嘴
and Richard and James resumed their bickering.
F-PACE是啥意思 听起来像家用清洁剂
What does F-PACE mean? It sounds like a domestic cleaning product.
我觉得你的宾利不要后视镜了
I think your Bentley would look better with alabaster lions
放两头大理石狮子比较配
instead of door mirrors.
我想问 你的手套箱是不是永远打不开了
I was going to ask if the glovebox is permanently locked shut in the Jag,
因为你钱包放在那儿
because that's where you keep your wallet.
宾利的前脸看起来很傻
The front of your Bentley looks silly.
看起来有点呆滞
It just looks a bit daft.
你怎么没接手布莱恩·修耶尔的工作呢
And why was it you didn't get Brian Sewell's old job?
布莱恩·修耶尔 英国评论家 收藏家
宾利Bentayga的选配列表里
Does the options list for your Bentley Bentayga
有没有假想祖先的油画呢
include oil paintings of imaginary ancestors?
对他们两人发出的噪音 我深表抱歉
I apologise for the noises these two are making.
我知道你们都坐在家里想
I realise you're all sitting at home going,
"他们争什么呢 我就想要揽胜" 肯定是这样
"What are they on about? I just want the Range Rover." Of course you do.
买宾利的唯一原因 就是你的唱片销量登顶
The only reason you'd buy the Bentley is cos your hip-hop record's gone to number one,
而买捷豹的唯一原因就是 你买不起揽胜
and the only reason you'd buy the Jag is cos you can't afford a Range Rover.
由于杰里米提到了钱的问题
Since Jeremy had brought up the subject of money...
我不知道他们是如何做到34000磅起卖
I don't know how they can sell you one of these for from 34 grand.
而且这辆 包含所有选配的
And this one, with everything on it,
除了V6机械增压引擎
quite apart from a V6 supercharged engine,
还有真皮内饰 iPhone接口
it's got leather everything, iPhone connectivity,
雷达测距 语音控制 电动后备箱
radar-distance control, voice control, electric boot,
戴在手腕上的神奇钥匙
magic key you wear on your wrist.
所有这些只要51000磅 怎么做到的
All of that still only costs 51 grand. How do they do that?
和别的一比 这就是世纪大钜惠啊
Next to everything else, it suddenly looks like the bargain of the century.
杰里米 这辆车比你的车好
Jeremy, this car is better than yours.
好吧 它并不是 对吗
Well, now, it just isn't, is it?
你就是个... 什么词来着
You're being a... What's the word?
丁丁
我们飞速穿过亲亲乡
We then flashed through the village of Kissing,
越快完事儿越好
getting it over with as quickly as possible.
然后经过摸摸寨
Then we went through Petting.
为了保证在睡觉前
And to make sure we reached erm...
能够上三垒
third base before bedtime,
我们决定打开导航
we decided to set our satnavs.
请说出国家名
SATNAV: Please name the country.
奥地利
Austria.
请说出城市名
SATNAV: Please name the city.
法 克银
Fu-cking.
请再说一次
SATNAV: Excuse me?
没有听清
SATNAV: Sorry?
你的目的地是 "色情" 吗
SATNAV: Is your destination Selking?
不 法啊克银
No. Fu-cking.
收到克拉克银 要选择哪条街道
SATNAV: Kraking has been accepted. Which street should I select?
没有听清
SATNAV: Sorry?
我没法说 人们听着呢
I can't say it. People are listening.
没有听清
SATNAV: Sorry?
谢天谢地 哈蒙德决定手动设置
Thankfully, Hammond had decided to program
他那便宜为本的导航系统
his bargain-basement system manually.
法
F.
啊
U.
克
K.
搞定了
It's gone in!
不久 我们穿过边境进入奥地利
And soon, we crossed the border into Austria.
奥地利非常非常美丽
It's very, very pretty, Austria.
想不通为什么希特勒心情那么差
No idea why Hitler was in such a bad mood.
终于 我们到达了
Eventually, we arrived...
啪啪屯
这里
here.
所以这是一路以来的高潮吗
So is this the climax of this stage of our journey?
这就是人们所向往的吗
Is it all it's cracked up to be?
啪啪屯
我就想知道这个
That's what I want to know.
因为第一次去的时候 总会有些失望
Cos often it can be a disappointment, the first time you go there.
我第一次来的时候 找不到进去的入口
The first time I came here, I couldn't find the way in.
一旦我们进入了...
Once we'd arrived in...
詹姆斯很渴望
...James was very keen
我们能够进入他宾利的后面
we should get in the back of his Bentley.
很不和谐的是 你坐在一辆宾利里
What's really incongruous about this is that you're very obviously in a Bentley.
所有东西都很宾利
All this looks very Bentley,
直到你看到下面这个旋钮上的图标
until you look down here and see these symbols on this control knob,
它显然是辆正儿八经的越野车
and it's very obviously a serious off-roader.
什么 那些图标
Oh, what, those symbols?
所以你可以设置为
So you can set it for
沼泽 雷区 圣诞或墨西哥模式吗 很好
swamp, minefield, Christmas or Mexico? Nice.
-是的 哈蒙德 -我来告诉你一些关于木材
- Yes, Hammond. - Shall I tell you something interesting about the wood,
或者其他可选木材的趣事吧
or one of the woods you can have in this?
它只在亚洲的一块峭壁上生长
It only grows on a cliff face in Asia,
他们要使用绳降来获取这些木材
and the way they get it is they have to abseil down it with their woodworking tools.
为什么不直接用林子里的树
Why don't they just use wood from a tree that grows in a field?
这儿有什么普通的东西吗
Is everything standard in here?
-没有 -没有吗
- No. - No?
-没有 -所以这辆车多少钱
- No. - So how much is this car?
-就这辆吗 -对
- This particular one? - Yes.
-大概212000英镑左右 -什么
- Is 212,000 and something. - What?
这说明这车的选配件
So that means the extras in this car
比哈蒙德的整辆捷豹还贵
cost more than Hammond's entire Jaguar?
-你捷豹多少钱 -差不多
- How much is your Jag? - About the same.
-捷豹带所有选配 -一共51450英镑
- What, that Jag with all the extras? - That is ￡51,450.
而这辆车有52000英镑的选配件
And this has got ￡52,000 worth of extras in it?
选配件就比整辆捷豹贵一点点
It's just a little bit more on extras than the entire Jag.
这很... 值
It's great... value.
-詹姆斯 我能说吗 -说吧
- Can I just say, James... - Yes, do.
我的确很喜欢这车的内饰
...I do quite like the interior of this car.
不 说真的 我喜欢这绗缝皮革
No, I do. I'll be honest. I like the quilted leather,
我喜欢这来自峭壁的木头 所有一切
I like the wood that comes from a cliff and all of that.
但这外观 抱歉 实在太丑了
But the exterior, I'm sorry, it's hideous.
-丑 巨丑 -好吧 等一下
- Ugly. Pig ugly. - Yeah, well, hang on a minute.
你还记得吗 在很久之前
Because, do you remember, and it is a long time ago,
当大陆GT刚发布的时候
when the Continental GT first came out,
所有人都觉得丑
we all thought that was hideous...
-是的 -现在我们都喜欢它了
- It was. - ...and now we all love it.
-难得我们统一意见 -是 真的
- It's one of the few things we agree on. - Yes. Yes, that's true.
但我觉得这更像你
But I think this is more like you.
当我最初遇见你时 我觉得你丑
When I first met you, I thought you were ugly.
而现在 我还是觉得你丑
And now I still think you're ugly.
来自帅气男子的苛刻批评
A crushing criticism from one so handsome.
-詹姆斯 -什么
- James? - What?
解开门锁
Unlock the doors.
詹姆斯 请开门
James, please unlock the doors.
我们在... 这个地方
We're in... this place.
在车后座上
In the back of a car,
两个人
together.
叹为观止啊 这些地方
It is remarkable, isn't it? All those places...
我确定 所有这些地名都是真的
I'm sure... All those place names are real.
-是真的 真地名 -是的
- They are real. Yeah, real places. - They really are.
地名都是真的
Those place names are real.
好的 我们晚点再看那没意义的测试
Anyway, we'll pick up that pointless test later on.
-不是没意义的 -它就是
- It's not pointless! - Yes, it is.
我已经完美地用内裤理论解释了
I already explained it perfectly well with the underpants thing.
我一会儿还会用更多地例子来阐释
And I shall be explaining using more demonstrations later on.
-噢 好了 -但现在到了
- Oh, good. - But now it is time
明星脑碰脑环节
for Celebrity Brain Crash!
好的 我们的嘉宾
Now, our guest...
今天的嘉宾
our guest today,
他执导了蝙蝠侠 人猿猩球
he directed Batman, Planet Of The Apes,
剪刀手爱德华
Edward Scissorhands.
而且 在上次水雷事故后
And, after last week's mine disaster,
他决定从水雷下方来演播室
he's decided to come to the studio underneath the mines
坐的是小型潜水艇
in a miniature submarine.
女士们先生们 蒂姆·波顿
Ladies and gentlemen, Tim Burton!
这是潜水艇 他在那儿
Here is the submarine. There he is,
在水雷下悄悄前进
sneaking underneath the mines.
-很明智 -他机智地游过来
- Clever. - As he heads cleverly towards us.
-他就在外面某处 -就在那儿 太棒了
- He's out there somewhere. - He's out there somewhere. This is fantastic.
-我们要跟他聊什么 -太多了
- What are we gonna talk to him about? - There's so much.
-你想问他什么 -有关圣诞夜惊魂的
- What do you want to ask him? -  About The Nightmare Before Christmas.
我最爱的圣诞电影
It's my favourite Christmas film.
是吗 我想问他和约翰尼德普搭档感觉如何
Is it? I want to know what it's like to work with Johnny Depp.
是啊 要问的太多了
Yeah, there's a lot to talk to him about.
噢 在吗
Oh, hello.
潜水艇的信号中断了
We've lost the feed somehow from the sub.
噢我的神啊  我的天
Oh, God Almight... Oh, my God!
哦不
Oh, no!
显然潜水艇遭遇了灾难性的事故
There's obviously been a catastrophic failure with the submarine.
-不知道什么引起的 -是水怪咬坏了
- No idea what could have caused it. - The monster's bitten it!
第一百次声明了 哈蒙德
For the hundredth time, Hammond,
没有尼斯湖水怪这种东西
there is no such thing as the Loch Ness Monster.
这就是说他来不了了
Does that mean he's not coming on, then?
船长 他的肺被灌满了冰水 已沉入了湖底
Well, James, his lungs have filled with icy water, he's sunk to the bottom,
他的身体被压成了一个乒乓球的大小
and his body is being compressed to the size of a Ping-Pong ball.
所以他来不了了
So that is a no.
没关系 我们还有个备用计划
It's OK, though, because we have a back-up plan.
-我们有吗 -是的
- Do we? - Yes.
你看 事情是这样的 这些日子里
You see, the thing is, these days,
-现在很多的性能车都有弹射起步 -是的
- a lot of performance cars have launch control. - Ah, yes. Yes.
它生效的方式是你把你的脚同时放在刹车和油门上
The way it works is you put your foot on the throttle and brake at the same time,
汽载计算机会精确计算出你需要多少转速
and the car's computer works out exactly how many revs you need
轮胎应该有多少滑移率
and exactly how much wheelspin to give the car
从而在你脚离开刹车同时
so that you get an absolutely perfect start
使你的车完成一个完美的起步
as soon as you just take your foot off the brake.
是的 所以我们在想 这究竟什么时候可以用得上
Yeah, and we were wondering, just when exactly can you use that?
如果你在市中心等红绿灯的时候 让车这样
If you're in a town centre at a set of lights going...
-懂我的意思嘛 -这有一点不文明
- Know what I mean? - It's a bit rude.
是的 就像这个小视频里所展示的
It is, as this short film explains.
请来一杯椰奶拿铁加焦糖
Coconut-milk latte with a caramel shot, please.
好的 一杯椰奶拿铁加焦-
OK, a coconut-milk latte with a caramel--
-要这有何用 -没用
- What is it for? - Pointless.
事情是这样的 你不能
The thing is, you can't...
你甚至都不能在赛道上用弹射起步
you can't even use launch control on a race track,
因为三四秒钟后 发动机的过热保护就会给发动机断油
because you can only engage it for three or four seconds before it cuts out.
而且你不知道灯什么时候变绿
And because you don't know when the lights are gonna go green,
你就不能准确的开始弹射起步 不是吗
you don't know when your three seconds start, do you?
的确 因为我们认为
Exactly, which is why we have decided
它是有史以来最没用的发明
it is the most pointless invention ever.
是的 说到没有意义
Yes, and talking of pointless,
回到我们的片子上
let's get back to our film.
恩 我们对一辆揽胜和其他车做了路测
Er... We're road-testing a Range Rover and some other cars.
从德国的紫薇村开始
We began in the German village of Wank,
计划穿越亲亲乡和摸摸寨
and the plan was to go through Kissing and Petting
前往我们的终点领证村
towards Wedding, which was our destination.
是的 我们开始行动并决定留在啪
Yes, and we pick up the action having decided to spend the night in Fu--
第二天我们在这被露水浸润的小镇醒来
We woke the next morning in this dew-kissed village.
在结束了颇为尴尬的早餐之后
And over a rather awkward breakfast,
大猩猩发布了一段言论
Clarkson made an announcement.
我不想伤害或不尊重谁
I don't mean to be hurtful or disrespectful,
但是 恩
but erm...
-说呀 别吞吞吐吐 -好吧 这
- Go on, spit it out. - Well, it's...
就因为我们住这里
just because we've been here,
啪啪屯
并不意味着我们就必须要去领证
doesn't mean we necessarily have to go on to Wedding.
啥
Aw!
我说的是我 不是你
It's me, it's not you.
他说的没错 到目前一切都很顺利
No, he's right. It's been going so well.
但如果我们去领证
And if we go on to Wedding,
我们就必须一直保持关系
we'll have to carry on and on and on,
穿过琐事 厌倦
through Routine, Boredom,
怨恨 分床
Resentment, Spare Bedroom,
诱惑 外遇
Temptation, Affair,
觉悟 悔恨 复仇
Discovery, Remorse, Revenge,
离婚 然后到死亡
Divorce, and then it's Death.
或者你可以试试摇一摇
Or you could turn off through Online Dating,
随便的约炮 事后无尽的悔恨
Meaningless Sex, Bottomless Regret,
破产 然后心肌梗塞
Financial Ruination, and then Heart Attack.
最终又回到死亡
And then you end up at Death anyway.
是的 哈蒙德 这就是为什么我建议
Exactly, Hammond. And that's why I'm suggesting
与其去领证
that instead of going to... Wedding,
我们还是去纽博格林吧
we go to the Nürburgring.
因为船长的车是唯一可以用德语的
Because James's car was the only one that spoke German,
所以他设置了导航
he set the satnav.
输入目的地 纽博格林
Ziel eingeben: Nürburgring.
我们出发吧
-  And then we set off.
很快 我们来到了Autobahn上
Soon, we were on Germany's Autobahns,
德国、奥地利、瑞士部分路段不限速的高速公路
不禁让人思考他们有多明智
which got us thinking about how sensible they are.
我们现在在Autobahn上
And here we are on the Autobahn.
没有限速
No speed limits.
很混乱吗 并不
Is it chaos? No.
即使你废除限速
If you remove the speed limits,
人们也不会突然以320kph的时速冲向桥柱
people don't all suddenly drive into bridge supports at 200 miles an hour.
我们才不傻 这就好比你在野生动物园
We're not that stupid. Just as if you leave the gate unlocked
把狮子区的门开着
at the lion closure at a safari park,
我们不会跑进去并在里面开野餐
we don't all run in and have a picnic.
在过去的15年里 英国的经济增长了58%
In the last 15 years, Britain's economy has grown by 58%,
而德国增长了102%
whereas Germany's has grown by 102%.
这是因为我们都开32kph时人家开320kph
And that's because we're all doing 20 miles an hour and they're doing 200.
速度对商业有益
Speed is good for business,
还能拯救生命
and it saves lives as well.
因为当我们行驶在英国的公路上时
Because when we drive down the motorway in Britain,
我们观察每个台架来看是否有测速相机
we're looking at all the gantries to see if they have speed cameras,
或者看自己的车速表来确保自己没有超速
or we're looking at our speedometers to make sure we're not breaking the limit.
我们没有好好看着路
We're not looking where we're going.
对限速的严格执行会要人命啊
Heavily enforced speed limits kill people.
Autobahn还让我们思考
The Autobahn also got us thinking
时间是怎么改变了SUV的阵营
about how times have changed on the SUV front.
这真的很惊人 一辆越野车
It is amazing, really, that an off-road vehicle
可以坐起来如此稳定
can feel this stable,
如此扎实 我想就是这个词
this planted, I think the word is.
因为在不远的过去
Because it's not that long ago,
如果你想想早期的揽胜的那个样子
if you think about early Range Rovers and the like,
开快了其实是很吓人的
going fast was actually quite frightening.
他们的遮阳板上有贴纸 你们记得吗
They had stickers on the sun visors, do you remember,
上面有一个翻车的图片
with a picture of the car toppling over.
禁止急转弯
"Avoid sudden swerves."
是的 我完全忘了那个贴纸
Yes, I'd completely forgotten
其实你是对的 的确如此
about that sticker, but you're right, it did.
如果你转动方向盘 这辆车会翻过来
"If you operate the steering wheel, this vehicle will fall over."
-伙计们 -怎么了
-  Chaps? -  What?
这里没有限速对吧
There are no speed limits, right?
所以我们可以让我们的车跑到极速
So we are allowed to go as fast as our cars will go.
但是谁真敢这么做
But who dares actually do that?
谁敢跑到极速
Who dares go the fastest?
好 如果你们想玩的话 我也要掺和了
Right, if we're going to play that game, I might even join in.
好啊
Bang on.
继续 詹姆斯 你自便
Go on, James. Help yourself.
走起 299km/h 极速 -真的?
- There you go, 187, top speed. -  Really?
问题是 你出发的时候就在我后面 现在你还在我后面
The thing is, you were behind me when you started and you still are behind me.
-我的极速是304km/h -哦 我去! 你开不了那么快
- I did 190. - Oh, for God's sake! You didn't.
这比你车的极速要快
That's faster than your car will go.
为了结束这场哔哔
In order to put a stop to this nonsense,
我让大家在下一个服务区停了下来
I made us pull in at the next service station.
好的 小相机
Right, small cameras.
我们把这个对着仪表盘 这样就能看见仪表盘了
We fix these to the dash where they can see the speedo,
所以就不会有作弊了
and then there's no cheating.
为什么你牵了只狗
Why have you got a dog?
我会告诉你们的 跟我来
I shall show you. Follow me.
如果你想要一只宠物
If you want a pet,
你可以买一些贵的
you can have something expensive,
比如带着银项链的鬣鳞蜥
like an iguana with a silver necklace.
或者你也可以买一些便宜的 比如蚂蚁
Or you can have something cheap, like an ant.
-什么蚂蚁? -那个蚂蚁
-  What ant? - That ant.
或者靠你的常识 买一只拉布拉多
Or you can use your common sense and have a labradog.
在我机智的讲解结束之后
With my clever demonstration over,
我们重回高速
we got back on the motorway
还装上了哈蒙德的诚实相机
and mounted Hammond's honesty cameras.
但我还有个作弊的好办法
I've got a good way of cheating still.
因为如果我按下这个按钮 看好了
Because if I push this button here, watch,
我的速度就会变到公里每小时
my speedometer changes to kilometres an hour.
他永远不会知道
He'll never know.
杰里米 你装上相机的时候
And Jeremy, while you're setting your camera up,
别想着把你的显示调到km/h
don't think about changing your display to km/h
所以你的数字就会更大了
so you get a bigger number.
验证极速的时刻到了
It was now time to begin the speed trials.
走起 来干票大的
Here we go. Going for a big one.
进入到一个速度和荣耀的世界
Into a world of speed and glory!
加油 奥迪 你一定要懂我啊
Come on, Audi. You must be able to see me.
加油
Come on, come on, come on.
让开啊 你在一辆奥迪里 加油
Out of the way. And you in the Audi. Come on.
随着交通顺畅起来
As the traffic eased,
哈蒙德叩开了240km/h的大门
Hammond was knocking on the door of 150 miles an hour.
那是237km/h了
That's 148.
238km/h
Forty-nine.
而我 也开始慢慢逼近
And I, too, was getting close.
240km/h快到了了 现在任何时候都可能到240km/h
150 coming up. 150 any minute now.
加油 抓住它
Come on, stretch it, stretch it, stretch it, stretch it, stretch it.
不幸的是 我们很难知道船长跑了多快
Sadly, it was hard to say how fast James was going,
因为他是个智障
because he's an imbecile.
哦耶 那个大数字来了
Oh, yeah! That big number's coming up.
达成挑战242km/h
Got to beat 151.
靠!
Shit!
为什么它就快不过那个速度了?
Why won't it go any faster than that?
加油啊!
Come on!
为啥你快不过237km/h?
Why won't you go any faster than 148?
最终 繁忙的路面终结了这场重要的比赛
Eventually, heavy traffic ended this important test.
好吧 鉴于我们身陷堵车之中
Right, as we are in a traffic jam,
我也该告诉你们谁赢了
I may as well give you the results of Who Dares Wins.
理查德 哈蒙德 250km/h
Richard Hammond, 155 miles an hour.
我的揽胜最高238km/h
I maxed the Range Rover at 149.
而船长 由于他是个唠叨的白痴
And James May, because he's a blithering idiot,
6000转
6,000rpm.
白痴的车还烧光了油
The idiot's car had also drained its tank,
所以当他加油的时候
so while he was filling up,
我开始了另一场机智的证明
I set up another of my clever demonstrations.
先生们 显而易见
Gentlemen, observe.
你可以买非常贵的太阳镜
You can buy very expensive sunglasses.
这种是用纯金做的
These ones are made from real gold.
或者你还可以买非常便宜的太阳镜
Or you can buy very cheap sunglasses.
但是应该怎么做呢
But what do we all do?
我们都买雷朋
We all have Ray-Bans.
你知道你这样让人很不爽吗
You do know you're just being irritating, don't you?
一谈到你的车 你只会扯到 内裤
All you've actually told us about your car is something to do with underpants,
鬣鳞蜥和太阳镜
iguanas and sunglasses.
-我只是就事论事 -才不是!
- I'm just saying. - Well, don't!
回到路上 我们继续跟着詹姆斯
Back on the move, we continued to follow James
踏上去纽伯格林的旅途
on our journey to the Nürburgring.
但是过了一会儿 我开始有点担心
But after a while, I started to worry.
他在往哪走?
Where's he going?
为什么我们从高速上下来了?
Why have we turned off the motorway?
您已到达目的地
Sie haben das Ziel erreicht
-詹姆斯... -怎么了?
- James... - What?
嗯 我就直说了吧
Well, I'm going to get straight to the point.
这不是纽伯格林
This is not the Nürburgring.
这是纽伦堡
It's Nuremberg.
-呃 好吧 是的 但是 -没有"呃 好吧"的话
- Ah, well, yes, but-- - There's no "Ah, well" about it.
是这样 我实际上不会说德语
The thing is, I can't actually speak German,
只会说近朱者赤近墨者黑之类的话
only the bit about hands being wet because he's under a waterfall.
但是纽伯格林的英语德语发音是一样的
But Nürburgring is the same in English as it is in German.
注释：其实不太一样
我在我车里用德语和语音控制交流
I did it with voice control in German with my car.
设置到德国后 我说纽伯格林 它闪了一下
It was set to German. I said Nürburgring and it went "blink"
-然后我说了"是的" 但是这个名字很相似   -别再责备车了!
- and I said, "Yes." But it's a similar name. - Don't blame the car!
好吧 是我没有准确发音
Well, I didn't pronounce it properly.
你这解释就好像因为我俩名字都是"J"开头所以就容易搞混了
That's like muddling up our names cos they both begin with J.
好了 我们别接着吵了
Look, let's not get all bogged down
就因为一个大傻X
with who's been a massive idiot
而且他说的话起不到任何正面作用
and despite what he claims can't do anything properly.
-没用 -我们可以找个附近的赛道代替一下
- Nothing. - Let's instead look for a race track near here.
为啥不去试着找一个呢?
Why don't we try and find one?
而这就是哈蒙德找到的赛道
And that is exactly what Hammond did.
在哪?
Where?
嗯 它就在你们周围 看 我已经标出来了
Well, it's all around you. Look, I've marked it out.
看 它绕着那 从那上去 沿着那边走
Look, it goes around there and up there and along there,
然后从那里下去 从那再绕回来
and then down there and round there.
这实际上不是个赛道 不是么
It's not really a track, is it?
不 它更好 这是场拉力赛
No, it's better. It's rallying.
这是有史以来第一场纽伦堡拉力赛
This will be the first ever Nuremberg Rally.
呃 不是 确实是第一场么
Well, not the... absolute first ever.
他说的对
He's right.
你们想过没 如果我们在这赛车
Do you imagine, if we did motorcycling round here,
这将会是史上第一次纽伦堡审判
it would be the first ever Nuremberg Trials?
我们可以试一下
Well, we could give it a go.
学会走路之前别跑
Let's not run before we can walk, eh?
由于哈蒙德的路线上布满了扭曲的弯道
Since Hammond's course featured twisting bends,
松散的路面
loose surfaces,
峭壁 还有成堆的巨石
sheer drops and piles of enormous rocks everywhere,
所以练习圈就很必要了
some practice laps were in order.
这里要慢因为这块尘土飞扬
Slightly slow there cos I go round a dusty one,
然后这里是...我也不知道
and then this is... I have no idea.
"危险" 好吧 我会记住的
"Danger." Right. I'll take note of that.
我可不想从这摔下去
I don't want to fall off there.
我去 我真不想从这摔下去
Oh, shit. I really don't want to fall off there.
现在 这块真是很吓人
Now, this bit is really scary.
耶
Yeah.
这有点吓尿了的节奏
That's a bit of a trouser-changer.
这可真是有趣啊
Ooh! Now, this is quite interesting,
因为在正常情况下
cos in normal use,
这台捷豹所有的动力都被输送到后轮
all of the power is sent to the rear wheels in the Jag.
但是它能把最多50%的动力
But it can then send power,
输送到前轮
up to 50% of it, to the front wheels.
好吧 在这里我稍有疏忽就会酿成大错
Right, this is where I can go very wrong if I'm not careful.
卧槽
Oh, shit.
与此同时 大猩猩决定他不需要练习
Clarkson, meanwhile, had decided he didn't need to have a practice.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
这是等哈蒙德回来之后的豆子演示
It's my baked beans demonstration for when Hammond gets back.
因为超市有便宜豆子
Because we've got cheap supermarket beans,
还有贵的...
then expensive...
哦天 我可没工夫搞这个
Oh, God. I haven't got time for this.
然后 中间是揽胜...
And then, in the middle, the Range Rover...
哦!
Oh!
随着练习结束
With practice over,
哈蒙德准备开始跑计时圈
Hammond lined up on the beginning line for his timed lap.
理查德·哈蒙德 准备出发 三 二 一
Richard Hammond, begin in three, two, one.
走！
Go!
走起
Here we go.
加油啊 哈蒙德 集中注意力
Now, come on, Hammond. Concentrate.
哦! 漂亮的飞跃漂移
Oh! That was beautiful lift-off oversteer.
稍带刹车 然后...
A little bit of a brake, and then...
哦! 这里太快了
Ooh! That's too fast there.
我有点吓尿了
I just had a wee.
好 我们预测一下他会说啥
Right, let's predict what he's saying in there.
他会说牵引力控制系统不能真正关闭
He'll say the traction control won't be turned off properly.
因为牵引力控制没法完全关闭
Cos you can't turn the traction control off completely.
他会说 "我需要动力但是不够"
He'll say, "I need power and there isn't any!"
加油啊 动力都去哪了
Come on! Where's the power?
给我动力啊
Give me power! Give me power!
现在 这个... 卧槽
Now, this one... Oh, shit.
这确实有点快了
This is the really fast bit.
加油啊 宝贝! 加油 这就对了 给我动力
Come on, baby! Come on. That's it. Give me power.
高速进入直道
Going in with big speed here.
现在 提前刹车
Now, brake early, early, early, early, early,
然后转进去
and then turn in.
搞定
Bury it.
我会快他十万八千里
I'm gonna be miles faster than him.
好吧 可你都没有练习过
Well, you haven't even done any practice.
-我知道 -说实话没那么容易
- I know. - It's honestly not that simple.
没错 是这样
Yes, it is.
加油啊!
Come on!
尽她所能 就是这样 走起
Giving it all she can. That's it, there you go.
小小地爆发 然后冲线
Little burst and across the line.
5分56秒整
Five minutes 56 dead.
-很好吗 -我不知道
- That good? - I don't know.
-5分56 -整
- Five 56. - Dead.
好 或者 不 你们看到最后一段路了吗
Yes! Or no! Did you see me at that last bit?
牵引力控制让我无法释放所有马力
The traction control just wouldn't let me put the power down there at all.
还停下了 你们看见我停下了吗
It stopped! Did you see me stop there?
-你为啥拿了个秒表？-给他计时
- Why have you got a stopwatch? - To time him.
不不 看
No, no, no, no. Look.
-今天几号 4月26号 -好的 知道了
- What date is it? April 26th. - Oh, yeah. Yeah, OK.
-4月26号... -不 一个更好的主意
- April 26th at... - No, a better idea.
我们为什么不每天在这顶上计日子呢
Why don't we just chalk marks on the roof for every day?
-每次太阳升起来的时候 记一个 -好
- Every time the sun comes up, OK, another mark. - Right.
詹姆斯 梅 你可以出发了
James May, you may begin
三 二 一
in three, two, one.
出发
Now.
船长为了英国和德国驾驶宾利出发了!
And May is off for Great Britain and Germany in the Bentley!
-他不喜欢高 -不 他不喜欢高
- He doesn't like heights. - No, he doesn't like heights.
-他不喜欢速度 -或者滑滑的东西
- He doesn't like speed. - Or slippery stuff.
所以...所有他讨厌的东西
So... everything he hates.
尽管环境险恶
Despite the hostile environment,
我决心掘地三尺
I was determined to dig deep
来彰显宾利的荣耀
for the honour of the Bentley badge.
好滑
Slidey, slidey, slidey.
好的 碎石路面
Yes, Tarmac.
你... 你听见了吗?
Did you... Did you hear that?
那是来自船长的响胎
That was tyre squeal from James May.
上坡
Up the ridge.
降一档
Knock it down a cog.
哦 我天
Oh, my God.
天哪!
Blimey!
这不是船长风格啊 不是么?
That wasn't very James May-ish, was it?
他这样会把自己吓死的
He'll have frightened himself to death.
刚那段有点疯狂
That's the dippy bit.
看看这个
Look at this!
哦 他腾空了 他居然腾空了
Oh! He got air! He got air!
我觉得他是一心想赢啊
I think he's being committed.
杰里米 如果他赢我了怎么办
Jeremy, what if he beats me?
-要是他比你快  -是啊
- What if he beats you? - Yeah.
-你会蒙羞致死 我将狂笑不止  -嗯 好吧
- You'll die of shame and I'll die laughing. - Yeah, OK.
即便他如此努力 这老妇人在弯道还是丢了时间
Try as he might, though, the old lady was losing time in the corners.
问题是 这车有两吨半重 还很长
The trouble is, it is a two-and-a-half-tonne fairly long car,
你没法改变物理定律
and you can't change the laws of physics.
天哪 这可不妙
Cor! That's not good.
哦 把它摆正 加油啊
Oh, get it straight! Come on!
哦 不 我过头了
Oh, no! I overdid it.
6分16秒
Six minutes 16.
所以 他慢16
So he was 16...
18秒 但是他的车卖一百八十多万
18 seconds slower than you and his car is £212,000.
多吐槽些 写下来
Say some more of that stuff. Write it down.
终于轮到这里最好的车了
Finally, it was the turn of the best car here.
3 2 1
Three, two, one.
开始
Begin!
他连一个练习圈都没跑过
He hasn't... done a single practice lap.
我是说 一次都没有
I mean, not one.
牵引力控制关闭 这就好多了
Traction control off. That's better.
看好了
And watch this!
切进弯 很好地完成
Flick it in. Nicely done.
再往另外一边切出去
Flick it back the other way.
他开车的时候会是什么状态 谦逊
While he's driving, what do we think he's being? Modest?
谦卑  安静
Self-effacing? Quiet?
他可能什么都不说 他应该在专注中
He probably isn't saying anything. He's probably concentrating.
好棒
Yes!
哦 天啊 我样样都行
Oh, God, I'm good at everything.
然而 为了赢得这场比赛
However, in order to win this contest,
我并不打算只靠我高超的驾驶技巧
I had no intention of relying only on my supreme skills.
事情是这样 捷豹和宾利都是公路车
You see, the thing is, the Jaguar and the Bentley were designed as road cars
再给他们一点越野能力
and then given some off-road ability.
然而揽胜从设计伊始就是一台越野车
Whereas the Range Rover was designed as an off-road car,
后来又增强了它的路面性能
and then given some ability to work on the road.
这只是细微的区别
It's only a subtle difference,
但这意味着我不用按照常规
but it means I don't have to follow the beaten track.
我能抄个近道
I can take shortcuts.
这车非常聪明
It's such a clever car, it really is.
它能感知到它正在驶过的地形
This car senses what sort of terrain it's driving over,
以此来决定差速锁是锁止还是打开
and then engages or disengages the differentials accordingly.
开宾利或者捷豹可来不了这里
You could not come up here in the Bentley or the Jaguar.
-好安静啊 我听不到 -他此刻在干嘛
- It's quiet. I can't hear it. - What's he in at the moment?
一条裤子 几罐豆子 拉布拉多
A pair of pants? Tin of beans? Labrador?
还会有更蠢的
There'll be another stupid...
你的这些都是大路货 我的才是最好的
"You get ordinary ones and mine's just the best."
揽胜的涉水深度
The Range Rover can wade through water
将近一米深
nearly a metre deep.
看看啊
And look at it!
多好的一辆车啊
What a machine you are!
现在 我就要速速窜上山了
Now we just pump back up the hill.
马力
Power!
马力啊
Power now!
-他在那里   -哎
- There he is. - Hey?
-不对 等等  -是的 你看 他在那里
- No, hang on a minute. - No, he's there, look.
-是啊 但是  -咋了
- No, but... - What?
冲线
And across the line.
他几乎比你快两分钟
He's almost two minutes quicker than you were.
这不可能
That's not possible.
-你是怎么做到的 -啥玩意儿
- How did you do that? - What?
-这个 -你的车全湿了 本不该如此
- That. - A, your car's all wet, which it shouldn't be.
此外你几乎比哈蒙德快了两分钟
And you're almost two minutes faster than Hammond.
是的 但是 你看 事情是这样的
Yes, but, you see, the thing is,
你能买一台便宜的车 比如说捷豹
you can buy a cheap car, like a Jaguar,
或者你能买一台贵的车
or you can buy an expensive car,
就像宾
like a Bent--
作弊 作弊 他就是在作弊
Cheat! Cheat! He just cheated.
浪费时间 这整部片子
A total waste of time, that whole film.
完全浪费时间 揽胜 快了两分钟
A total waste of time. Range Rover, two minutes faster.
一句话 你作弊了
You cheated, simple as that.
那啥 你看 如果我们把这个争论先放一放
Anyway, look, if we can just put the bickering aside for one moment,
我不得不说 这个小捷豹
I have to say, that little Jag was,
真的很棒 它的设计师
and it really was, brilliant. And it was designed
是一个本地的小伙子 叫Ian Callum 生于邓弗里斯
by a local boy, Ian Callum, born in Dumfries.
除此之外 他也设计了阿斯顿马丁DB7
He didn't just do that. He also styled the Aston Martin DB7,
DB9 Vanquish 和 福特Puma
the DB9, the Vanquish, the Ford Puma,
还有 考斯沃斯版本的Escort
the Escort Cosworth.
-于是 他是不列颠人 -基本上是的
- Yeah, he's British. - Basically, yeah.
好吧 几乎如此
Well, pretty much.
确实 确实
He is. He is.
但是 不幸的是 他的新车没有揽胜好
Anyway, sadly, his new car isn't as good as a Range Rover.
别和我争 它不行
Don't argue. It isn't.
带着对他彻彻底底的失望 是时候结束了
And on that terrible disappointment for him, it's time to end.
感谢收看
Thank you so much for watching.
感谢你们的到来
Thank you all so much for coming.
我们下次再会  再见
We'll see you next time. Goodbye.